LISA M. NOETZEL

lisanoetzel.github.io • lisa.noetzel@gmail.com • (202) 735-1229

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Full-Stack graduate from Georgia Tech. Experienced educator with demonstrated history of success in managing programs/projects from conception to completion. Expert at curriculum development, enrollment management, e-learning, assessment creation, and interpreting quantitative/qualitative data to optimize performance outcomes.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

COLLEGE OF COASTAL GEORGIA

2010 -Present

Program Director (BA Foreign Languages) / (AA Modern Languages)

- Administered AA in Modern Languages then collaborated with Valdosta State and Clayton State universities to create online BA programs in French and Spanish
- Revitalized course enrollment (traditional: 300%; online: 500%), majors/minors growth (900%), and delivered new language offerings (growth: 200%)

Associate Professor / Assistant Professor (2010 – 2012)

- Chaired search committees, interviewed candidates, and hired teaching faculty
- Supervised assessment of foreign language curriculum for SACS regional accreditation
- Advised AA and BA majors/minors

WASHINGTON COLLEGE

2002 - 2009

FLRC Director (2003 - 2005)

- Managed Foreign Language Resource Center, budgeted removal and replacement of analogdigital equipment
- Trained lab assistants, submitted work authorization procedures, scheduled lab assignments

Assistant Professor

- Developed curricula in linguistics, Spanish, and Italian
- Created quantitative/qualitative rubrics for departmental assessment and MSCHE regional accreditation

EDUCATION

GEORGIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY	Atlanta, GA	2019
Certificate: Full-Stack Web Development PENNSYLVANIA STATE UNIVERSITY	University Park, PA	2002
Ph.D: Spanish		
NEW YORK UNIVERSITY	New York, NY	1992
MA: French		1000
ROLLINS COLLEGE	Winter Park, FL	1990
BA: International Relations & Foreign Languages		

SKILLS

Web Development

- Bootstrap, CSS, HTML5,
- JS, JQuery, Moment.js, Node.js
- Firebase, MySQL, Wiggle

Communicative / Technological

- Written & Oral fluency in 4 languages
- MS Word, Excel, PowerPoint
- Blackboard, D2L